Today I will talk about the 1.1.1 criterion of web content Accessibility
which concerns non-textual content
before going into specifics and understanding what this criterion is about
you must first understand what the non-textual content is
in fact, non-textual content concerns all the content within a web page
which is presented to the user and has a text alternative
and that has a textual alternative that fulfills the equivalent purpose
there are several specific types of non-textual content
for example the illustrative photos
which are simply images of objects, people or places
of background images
which are obtained using CSS
and therefore it is not possible to specify an alternate text value
however it is important to use an alternate background for cases where the image
cannot be displayed
icons
they are small pictograms, images that convey specific information
and obviously they must be used consistently, within a page or site
charts and diagrams
they usually represent numerical data
consequently a possible alternative text could consist
in a brief summary of the main trends
or if necessary, provide a more detailed description of the text
using the description field in the advanced image properties tab
captcha
captcha stands for "Fully automated turing test to distinguish machines from people
and is usually used as a security check on web pages
to distinguish humans from malicious software
which, however, can represent an obstacle to accessibility
in fact, these are images that require users to describe what they see
in order to pass a safety test
therefore providing alternative text for the image is obviously not possible
and alternative solutions will need to be considered
the purpose of the non-textual content
information on a web page can be provided in various non-textual formats
such as images, videos and animations
however blind people
or with severe visual impairment they are unable to see non-textual content
but they can still access the textual content
read using a screen reader
or presented in tactile form by a braille device
so thanks to the availability of textual alternatives to the content
all people can access the site
how to meet the criterion
for graphic and static elements the basic requirement is
in providing an equivalent text alternative
and this can be done in the ALT text
and then make small descriptions about the image
now let's go and see
here we have a normal site with images
that have already incorporated some small descriptions
very detailed but that center the lens of the photo
though if we notice the code
nothing has been specified for the ALT text
so, here for example I am talking about our residences
let's put "residence" at the ALT attribute
and so on for all ALT tags
so here we talk about ski areas
to the ALT tag we can put "districts"
here we have our territory, we can put "territory"
and so on
this mechanism must be done for all ALT attributes
creating good text alternatives
then there are various forms of non-textual content
hence the value of the alt text
depends on the role of the graphic on the page
textual alternatives should be concise
but clearly convey essential information
provided by non-textual content